[{"id": "5a4a970b61d1b4d384d5d67f", "question": "Which Disney film marked Donald Duck's debut?", "answer": "The Wise Little Hen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a821", "question": "Botany Bay lies off the coast of what country?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6017382d44491cbd7c5a1795", "question": "What was the first U.S. state to ban billboards?", "answer": "Hawaii -- Billboards were banned in Hawaii in 1927.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd69fcd6c0f9723ab15cb2f", "question": "What was the first book sold on Amazon?", "answer": "\"Fluid Concepts And Creative Analogies\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ef", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows\" what does the acronym RAB stand for?", "answer": "Regulus A. Black", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afe5", "question": "Who did George Bush Sr. defeat in the election in 1988?", "answer": "Michael Dukakis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c993fbde8045e48466ef", "question": "What is a group of jelly fish called?", "answer": "A smack", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b060", "question": "When did the Panama Canal open?", "answer": "1914", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600242794be4723ccac22186", "question": "Atticus Finch is the name of the narrator\u2019s father in which classic 1960 novel?", "answer": "\"To Kill a Mockingbird\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b605", "question": "Which impressionist featured his wife Camille, in \"The Woman in the Green Dress\"?", "answer": "Claude Monet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b787", "question": "What food is usually left out for Santa Claus on Christmas Eve?", "answer": "Milk and cookies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea33e8ff048f679a45aaf2", "question": "Why is most pollen yellow?", "answer": "To attract bees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b3231a6bf195a31e15d7386", "question": "Who shared the 1978 Nobel Peace Prize with Menachem Begin?", "answer": "Mohamed Anwar Al-Sadat", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5901db00709c1c34536e6eb0", "question": "Ben Bailey is best known as the host of what game show?", "answer": "Cash Cab", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010ca4c0775fa611bce67f6", "question": "What is another name for rubbing alcohol?", "answer": "Isopropyl alcohol -- It is a germicide that is effective against bacteria, viruses, and fungi.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d6e", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"A Tale of the Christ\"?", "answer": "Ben-Hur", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9f7", "question": "What was the name of the first orbiter of NASA's space shuttle program?", "answer": "Enterprise", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febaa167e83c707845b20db", "question": "Where was the world's first public aquarium?", "answer": "London", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd6a0a06c0f9723ab15cb36", "question": "What was the inspiration behind a 12-person jury?", "answer": "The 12 Apostles of Jesus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a739", "question": "Klamath Lake is the largest lake in which US state?", "answer": "Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59029e1bcad1ec93f27df753", "question": "Who wrote the essay \"A Nice Cup of Tea\"?", "answer": "George Orwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaa2", "question": "Which city is the capital of the Italian region of Tuscany?", "answer": "Florence", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6aa", "question": "What cave, found in central Kentucky, is the world's longest cave system?", "answer": "Mammoth Cave", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a164", "question": "Who is Reginald Kenneth Dwight otherwise known as?", "answer": "Elton John", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a649", "question": "Lincoln is the capital of which state?", "answer": "Nebraska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bead", "question": "\"Tennis bracelets\" are so named because of a 1987 incident involving what athlete?", "answer": "Chris Evert", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd66b3fa5bfecdd737e0883", "question": "What is the name of a full moon that occurs in January?", "answer": "Wolf moon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b915", "question": "What breakfast favorite, with a hole in the middle, is equal to 4 slices of bread?", "answer": "A bagel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133914d", "question": "Who was the Greek god of blacksmiths?", "answer": "Hephaestus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b36d", "question": "Which country was the first to allow women to vote in 1893?\u00a0", "answer": "New Zealand\u00a0", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd66d94a5bfecdd737e08a3", "question": "What was the most popular month for weddings in the U.S. in 2019?", "answer": "October", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339101", "question": "Which famous composer wrote the opera \"Carmen\"?", "answer": "Georges Bizet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f13", "question": "What author created Middle-Earth?", "answer": "J. R. R. Tolkien", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59cdb16e65ff7d326b622a6a", "question": "During which month is the longest day in the Southern hemisphere?", "answer": "December", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac57", "question": "Which ship was Titanic's sister ship?", "answer": "The Olympic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada0", "question": "Who was better known as \"Sundance Kid\"?", "answer": "Harry Alonzo Longabaugh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc9a", "question": "What sport's lingo uses the term \"Schuss\"?", "answer": "Skiing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b123", "question": "How old was Christopher Columbus when he made his famous voyage in 1492?", "answer": "40", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3a1", "question": "What year was fashion designer Gianni Versace killed?", "answer": "1997", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ddf", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"alcohol\"?", "answer": "Arabic", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8b7", "question": "In what city would you find Rock Creek Park?", "answer": "Washington, D.C.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2cfa22596a59cbdfbd371", "question": "Who said, \"Do I not destroy my enemies when I make them my friends\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe0da86fcbed638185eaa05", "question": "Where can you find the world\u2019s smallest penguin?", "answer": "Tasmania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4e9", "question": "What popular spirit can be made from potatoes?", "answer": "Vodka", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb60d05dad637d903c882c", "question": "The Rungnado 1st of May Stadium, built in honor of the May Day holiday, exists in which country?", "answer": "North Korea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab1c03baab681b0929219d", "question": "What year did Porsche introduce the 911?", "answer": "1963", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f20a01dd7bf43be5e80a", "question": "What hairstyle did First Lady Jacqueline Kennedy make popular?", "answer": "Bouffant", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8d1", "question": "What is the function of the Thyroid Gland?", "answer": "To regulate growth and metabolism\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b2", "question": "When did the Jallianwahla Bagh massacre take place?", "answer": "April 13, 1919", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ea", "question": "In which Star Wars movie does Darth Vader reveal that he is Luke Skywalker's father?", "answer": "The Empire Strikes Back", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b31a", "question": "Who was the first man to appear on the cover of Playboy Magazine?", "answer": "Peter Sellers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c755", "question": "What is the opposite of insulin and secreted by the pancreas?", "answer": "Glucagon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aea3", "question": "What was the nationality of the first man to conquer the summit of mount Everest?", "answer": "New Zealander", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d6d", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"And What Alice Found There\"?", "answer": "Through the Looking-Glass", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf52", "question": "What is the name of the Danish parliament?", "answer": "The Folketing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c17e", "question": "What is the name of the leading female singer in an opera?", "answer": "Prima donna", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cd8", "question": "According to J.K. Rowling, in what year was Albus Dumbledore born?", "answer": "1881", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8b3dc01dd7bf43be5e7b6", "question": "What city created a new beachfront when it hosted the Olympics?", "answer": "Barcelona", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338928", "question": "Which rock group charted \"Land of Confusion\" in 1986?", "answer": "Genesis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c999", "question": "Which mole-like mammal has given its name to a mean spirited or bad tempered woman?", "answer": "Shrew\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8f65101dd7bf43be5e831", "question": "What was the only NBA team Michael Jordan played for other than the Chicago Bulls?", "answer": "Washington Wizzards", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1c0", "question": "What is the name of Mr. Krane's dog on the TV show \"Frasier\"?", "answer": "Eddie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bd05beb40191c55fd523fb4", "question": "True or False: A bearded dragon takes most of its peronality for its owner?", "answer": "True", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefbf506ce05a3942286efe", "question": "Who played the female lead in the film \"Man on Fire\"?", "answer": "Dakota Fanning", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b147", "question": "In what decade did the Dust Bowl devastate US Midwest farmers?", "answer": "1930's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdd9", "question": "What name is given to the full moon closest to the autumn equinox?", "answer": "Harvest moon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9f4a0ff048f679a45aac7", "question": "What is the largest object in the asteroid belt that lies between the orbits of Mars and Jupiter?", "answer": "Ceres", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5efa9496ccb363a2cbc5227a", "question": "Elton John sang that his \"future lies beyond\" what?", "answer": "The Yellow Brick Road", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e93397ccba3ffe45786c3", "question": "What food item does the painting technique \"Tempera\" commonly uses as a binder?", "answer": "Egg yolks", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c765", "question": "What term refers to a group of frogs?", "answer": "Army", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba6c", "question": "What round-bottomed cooking vessel did China introduce to the culinary world?", "answer": "The wok", "category": "general"}, {"id": "590722593745b36be73039fe", "question": "According to Futurama, what holiday is celebrated on December 25th in the year 3,000?", "answer": "Xmas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba1b", "question": "Who did Time magazine name as \"Man of the Year\" in 1979?", "answer": "Ayatollah Khomeini", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339293", "question": "What 2007 film follows the crew of the Icarus II as they attempt to reignite a falling sun?", "answer": "Sunshine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ee3208d98002fdd633d2", "question": "What is the literal meaning of the Dutch word \"brandewijn\"?", "answer": "Burned wine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e38", "question": "In what film is General Jack Ripper obsessed with America's \"precious bodily fluids\"?", "answer": "Dr. Strangelove or: How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the Bomb", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ac6", "question": "\"Blue Horseshoe loves Anacott Steel\" is a line from what movie?", "answer": "Wall Street", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590681a8ff9c0647b50a8096", "question": "What is the name of Beyonce\u2019s sixth studio album, released in April 2016?", "answer": "Lemonade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ed", "question": "How many pounds did Johnny Depp have to lose for the role of Edward Scissorhands?", "answer": "25", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acfc", "question": "What wiped out Napoleon's Caribbean troops, leading him to scrap plans to conquer the New World?", "answer": "Yellow Fever", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b706", "question": "What Christmas song's characters' eyes were made from coal?", "answer": "Frosty the Snowman", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d3", "question": "Who warned against the \"military-industrial complex\" in his famous farewell address?", "answer": "Dwight D. Eisenhower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbb9", "question": "What soft drink used the ad slogan \"Obey your thirst\" for almost two decades?", "answer": "Sprite", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f7475a9e54d890926f6f7", "question": "Buchaechum is a traditional Korean what?", "answer": "Fan dance", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60062c2fc9d816e292245c2a", "question": "How many paintings did Vincent Van Gogh sell during his lifetime?", "answer": "He created more than 900 paintings, yet sold only\u00a0one\u00a0during his lifetime, \"Red Vineyard at Arles\".", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e865fe83fe1f2a824bdc", "question": "The Chinese Exclusion Act was signed into law by which US president in 1882?", "answer": "Chester A Arthur", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fede0f56ce05a3942286dbf", "question": "In the film \"The Shawshank's Redemption,\" what was the name of the pet bird?", "answer": "Jake", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396df", "question": "In which country was Nicole Kidman born?", "answer": "United States", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60062d1ac9d816e292245c31", "question": "What landmark work came about from a friend's request for a self-portrait of Rene Magritte?", "answer": "\"The Son of Man\"\u00a0(A friend's request for a self-portrait of Rene Magritte, which was a man's face obscured by a piece of fruit.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a00c", "question": "What two Orlando Magic teammates made their screen debuts in \"Blue Chips\"?", "answer": "Shaquille O'Neal and Anfernee Hardaway", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b48d549076251badbeaa7", "question": "Who was the first African-American to travel in space?", "answer": "Guion Bluford -- On the third Challenger mission in 1983, he earned the distinction of being the first African-American in space.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa3a8fc73aa70ea0b70adf", "question": "What is the oldest city in the world?", "answer": "Damascus (The capital of Syria has evidence of continuous habitation dating back at least 11,000 years)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b405", "question": "What year was Olympic sprinter, Don Quarrie, born?", "answer": "1951", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ba", "question": "What country is the \"land of the lions\"?", "answer": "Singapore", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa31", "question": "What is the capital of Luxembourg?", "answer": "Luxembourg City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf1", "question": "In what year was famous designer Giorgio Armani born?", "answer": "1934", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339817", "question": "What singer was born Cherilyn Sarkisian?", "answer": "Cher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adf9", "question": "What was the first building in the world to have more than 100 floors?", "answer": "Empire State Building", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e16", "question": "At the end of \"The Da Vinci Code\", the Holy Grail is revealed to be buried at what popular spot?", "answer": "The Louvre Museum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b73d", "question": "According to the Dewey Decimal System, library books numbered in the 500s are part of what category?", "answer": "Science", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389b8", "question": "What musical instrument does Sherlock Holmes play for relaxation?", "answer": "Violin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb6", "question": "How many dot positions are there in each letter of the Braille alphabet?", "answer": "Six", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9bb7d364247bf200fb8a4", "question": "Which UK group won the 1981 Eurovision Song Contest?", "answer": "Bucks Fizz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af0e", "question": "The Battle of Bunker Hill occurred during what war?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdfba17003d27d341092bc3", "question": "What three countries border Luxembourg?", "answer": "France, Germany, and Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5901dc26709c1c34536e6eb4", "question": "What country was the music artist Rihanna born in?", "answer": "Barbados", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede0e66ce05a3942286dbd", "question": "In the film \"Schindler's List\" what city was the setting?", "answer": "Krakow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af24bf7844f4236002b95b2", "question": "Armenia is considered to be part of which continent?", "answer": "Asia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b72f", "question": "What beverage was the first American consumer product made widely available in the USSR?", "answer": "Pepsi-Cola", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ab99d1f21a8909e5c332d3e", "question": "What was Harold Lloyd Jenkins' stage name?", "answer": "Conway Twitty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396fa", "question": "Who starred as the Six Million Dollar Man?", "answer": "Lee Majors", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a843", "question": "In which US state is the Grand Coulee Dam?", "answer": "Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd6a47b6c0f9723ab15cb54", "question": "Who was USA' first female governor?", "answer": "Nellie Tayloe Ross", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b022", "question": "What world leader was Time magazine's \"Man of the Year\" for 1938?", "answer": "Adolf Hitler", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c321", "question": "Which planet is known as the red planet?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601de9f76b1208747aa7e9d5", "question": "In the Chinese zodiac, with which of the five elements is the snake associated?", "answer": "Fire -- It points to aggression and dominance.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a119", "question": "Which classic Hollywood western is based on the film \"Seven Samurai\"?", "answer": "The Magnificent Seven", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339460", "question": "What silent film star was \"The Tramp\"?", "answer": "Charlie Chaplin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b201", "question": "What ship was commanded by William Bligh?", "answer": "Bounty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1ad", "question": "Construction of the Colosseum began under the ruling of which emperor?", "answer": "Vespasian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca2d", "question": "Newton divided the visible spectrum into which seven colors?", "answer": "Red, orange, yellow, green, blue, indigo and violet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7cc", "question": "What bird is Britain's VTOL \"jump jet\" named for?", "answer": "The Harrier hawk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133893a", "question": "Who painted the Sistine Chapel ceiling?", "answer": "Michelangelo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf79", "question": "Pnigerophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Smothering", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a380", "question": "Which continent would you find Morocco in?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be37", "question": "How many players are there in a standard soccer team?", "answer": "Eleven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fffa58973838c5c8a417f26", "question": "What insects are sometimes called devil\u2019s darning needles?", "answer": "Dragonfly (They\u2019ve also been called darners and devil\u2019s arrows.)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58e2f5602e77afa695b03105", "question": "Mal\u00e9 is the capital of which Asian country?", "answer": "Maldives", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b590", "question": "What is by far the best known product by Victorinox?", "answer": "Swiss Army Knife", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a48", "question": "In the TV series, which one of the four main characters on \"Sex and the City\" had a baby?", "answer": "Miranda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aab6", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Finland?", "answer": "Whooper swan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c3e9a43ebfabb9c85d8a979", "question": "The meat pie, Tourtiere, originated in which country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea7a8dff048f679a45abec", "question": "What does the human lacrimal gland produce?", "answer": "Tears", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6014c988fbde8045e48466ee", "question": "Which farm animal can purr, similar to a cat, when they are happy?", "answer": "Turkeys make a variety of sounds, including a soft, rolling call when they are happy, which is called a purr.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a533", "question": "The Missouri River flows into what river?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b52e", "question": "What is the main difference between a Bloody Mary and a Bloody Caeser?", "answer": "Mary is made with Tomato juice and Caesar is made with Clamato juice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa5265c73aa70ea0b70b1a", "question": "The Po River is the longest river in which country?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f167f2f7c52aae91cc07c0", "question": "What is a brickfielder?", "answer": "Hot and dry Southern Australian wind", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a4d99ea08b8581f80b092b8", "question": "What month in 2017 did the United Kingdom begin Brexit Negotiations?", "answer": "March", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1b1", "question": "What instrument family does the French Horn belong to?", "answer": "Brass", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339265", "question": "What was Paul McCartney's Bond theme?", "answer": "Live and Let Die", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a46c", "question": "Tarifa is the southern most point on the mainland of which country?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ec", "question": "What was Daniel's last name in 1984's \"The Karate Kid\"?", "answer": "LaRusso", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f5660b33a95c66dc4fe75d", "question": "Which British opera festival was started in 1934?", "answer": "Glyndebourne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a291", "question": "Who became Yusuf Islam in 1977?", "answer": "Cat Stevens", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395f9", "question": "What is Uma Thurman's character known as in the Kill Bill series?", "answer": "The Bride", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d70a2596a59cbdfbd3b1", "question": "Who invented corn flakes?", "answer": "Dr. John Harvey Kellogg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a02e", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", what is Stewie's favorite TV show?", "answer": "Jolly Farm Revue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e38d71ef6c8a670a7957c5c", "question": "What South American city\u2019s citizens are known as \"Cariocas\"?", "answer": "Rio de Janiero", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597cd907e347d002c297e4ca", "question": "On which date is Epiphany celebrated in the traditional Western calendar?", "answer": "January 6", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff2574a31a458464a93c463", "question": "Which restaurant chain fooled the public on 1 April 1998 with the introduction of a fictional sandwich for left-handed people?", "answer": "Burger King released an ad for the fictitious \"Left-Handed Whopper\" on April Fool's Day of 1998.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "593c4b3ab8198b9a2b077961", "question": "The film \"Four Weddings and a Funeral\" was released in which year?", "answer": "1994", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c461", "question": "\"Ships of the desert\" are what?", "answer": "Camels", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a2b", "question": "Who became an animated Disney megastar after replacing Oswald the Lucky Rabbit?", "answer": "Mickey Mouse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c69c", "question": "Syncope is the medical term for what?", "answer": "Fainting", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ab", "question": "What bone, to which your ribs are attached, gets its name from the Greek for breastbone?", "answer": "Sternum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0e5", "question": "Which pasta is shaped like a bicycle?", "answer": "Biciclette", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394d6", "question": "Who was the first president of the Academy of Motion of Picture Arts and Sciences?", "answer": "Douglas Fairbanks Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b82d", "question": "What Hindu god is known as \"The Destroyer\"?", "answer": "Shiva", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338be4", "question": "What is the name of the controversial novel that was written by Salmon Rushdie?", "answer": "The Satanic Verses", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af9e", "question": "William de Tracy played a part in the murder of which \"chief overseer\"?", "answer": "Archbishop Thomas Becket", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecd73bec223966ae8f88d8", "question": "In Michael Phelps\u2019 last-ever Olympic relay, what stroke did he swim?", "answer": "Butterfly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe77075eec85e375820b2f9", "question": "Where is the \"Top of Europe\"?", "answer": "Jungfraujoch, Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e79", "question": "During what war was the novel \"Catch-22\" set?", "answer": "World War II", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e0", "question": "Who wrote the first three books of the \"Millennium\" novel series?", "answer": "Stieg Larsson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ec6", "question": "In what band did Roger, Andy, and John Taylor all play?", "answer": "Duran Duran", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be5c", "question": "Oldest son Al was the first ringmaster of what famous circus?", "answer": "Ringling Brothers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398d2", "question": "The Flintstones lived in what city?", "answer": "Bedrock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590089fbcf842fa4c4ba968e", "question": "Which band recorded the album titled \"Slippery When Wet\"?", "answer": "Bon Jovi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5990f88efa5fdd6dd25324ee", "question": "How many Great Lakes are there?", "answer": "Five", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5e3", "question": "What plant does the vanilla bean come from?", "answer": "The orchid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5909cc60bb53d1af658864e0", "question": "On which three days of the week is December 25th more likely to fall?", "answer": "Tuesday, Friday or Sunday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a627", "question": "Which state is directly south of Virginia?", "answer": "North Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ca3de244f0f6af5b066641", "question": "Andorra is part of which continent?", "answer": "Europe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e5", "question": "What is known as a \"Magnum Opus\"?", "answer": "The greatest, most popular or most renowned achievement of a writer, artist or composer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d03", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Barney Fife?", "answer": "Sheriff Andy Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a40d", "question": "Devil's Island, once the world's most notorious penal colony, is located off the coast of what country?", "answer": "French Guiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefa5326ce05a3942286ebb", "question": "How much did it cost to make the film \"Rocky\"?", "answer": "Approximately $1 million", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fce", "question": "Where did Aristotle believe the seat of intelligence was?", "answer": "Heart", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4a6", "question": "Which hills divide England And Scotland?", "answer": "Cheviot Hills", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b446", "question": "What year did Joseph Merrick, also known as Elephant Man, die?", "answer": "1890", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a047", "question": "What song was Hawaiin Don Ho most known for?", "answer": "Tiny Bubbles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937eeb208d98002fdd633d7", "question": "Who sang the hit song \"Confide in Me\" in 1994?", "answer": "Kylie Minogue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e1f", "question": "For an SNL monologue, who once played the banjo with an arrow through his head?", "answer": "Steve Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb58bd5dad637d903c8811", "question": "The Band-Aid supergroup was formed in 1984 to raise money for famine relief in what troubled African nation?", "answer": "Ethiopia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391fe", "question": "In which movie did Eddie Murphy play a character named Prince Akeem?", "answer": "Coming to America", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c383", "question": "The water moccasin snake is also known as what?", "answer": "Cottonmouth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5f8", "question": "How many natural satellites does Jupiter have?", "answer": "79", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e4b4fe83fe1f2a824bb6", "question": "At what conference did the Allies set the terms for the Japanese surrender?", "answer": "The Potsdam Conference", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febb7587e83c707845b212f", "question": "What were comets called in ancient Greece?", "answer": "Hairy stars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd96ec023c87fd04dd15e3c", "question": "When was the first commercial film screening?", "answer": "1895", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aae0", "question": "What is the capital of Sudan?", "answer": "Khartoum", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a043", "question": "John Oliver began hosting what show for HBO in 2014?", "answer": "Last Week Tonight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7c9", "question": "What country is also called Nippon by its citizens?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f5664733a95c66dc4fe761", "question": "In which film did Orson Welles play the role of Harry Lime?", "answer": "The Third Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60078b270eee65b76b9f2663", "question": "What was the original name for battle tanks?", "answer": "Landships (The name \"tank\" was due to the secrecy about its development project, which was leaked as research into water tanks.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e72cc9ed0874f1a5e2d1c24", "question": "What is Michael J. Fox\u2019s middle name?", "answer": "Andrew", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa39d9c73aa70ea0b70adc", "question": "The islands New Britain and New Ireland are part of what country?", "answer": "Papua New Guinea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59008e89cf842fa4c4ba96b3", "question": "On what sea did the \"Battle of Jutland\" take place?", "answer": "North Sea", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339703", "question": "In which country is the musical and film \"Mamma Mia\" set?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e4f", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"Amazing Grace and Chuck\"?", "answer": "Alex English", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd9662e23c87fd04dd15e01", "question": "What year was the first computer mouse prototype built?", "answer": "1964", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1f3", "question": "What year marked the debut of the Volkswagen Golf GTI?", "answer": "1976", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a935", "question": "What is the only nation that shares a land border with Qatar?", "answer": "Saudi Arabia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b589", "question": "What does a Turk call \"Turkish Delight\"?", "answer": "Lokum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c06e", "question": "In what decade was Montreal Canadien great Guy Lafleur born?", "answer": "1950s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133920f", "question": "What movie trivia is Sick Boy obsessed with in the movie \"Trainspotting\"?", "answer": "James Bond", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399e9", "question": "On what TV series did Katie Holmes first achieve stardom from 1998 to 2003?", "answer": "Dawson's Creek", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2fd", "question": "On the sitcom \"Happy Days\", the character of Matsuo Takahashi was better known by what name?", "answer": "Arnold", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4b6649076251badbeac4", "question": "Maya Angelou spoke at the inauguration of which U.S. President?", "answer": "Maya Angelou recited her poem \"On the Pulse of Morning,\" at President Bill Clinton's first inauguration in 1993.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390fa", "question": "Who wrote the 1991 novel \"The Deceiver\"?", "answer": "Frederick Forsyth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdc1259469bb8041d07a07b", "question": "What is Uranus' period of revolution around the Sun?", "answer": "84.02 Earth Years", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f14", "question": "What author created Wonderland?", "answer": "Lewis Carroll", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca81", "question": "From what animal fat was margarine first made from in the US?", "answer": "Beef", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2ab", "question": "What is a sump?", "answer": "A low space which collects undesirable liquids.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe0e45cfcbed638185eaa27", "question": "In which US city can you find \"Bubblegum Alley\"?", "answer": "San Luis Obispo, California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d2", "question": "How many claws does a domestic cat have?", "answer": "18", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d21", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"Days of Thunder\"?", "answer": "Car racing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c85a", "question": "What disease grounded astronaut Ken Mattingly from Apollo 13?", "answer": "The measles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdf2", "question": "What word has Beyonce Knowles defined as \"beautiful, bountiful and bounce-able\"?", "answer": "Bootylicious", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb668f5dad637d903c8838", "question": "The Maluku islands (informally known as the Spice Islands) belong to which country?", "answer": "Indonesia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a991", "question": "In what mountain range is Mount Ansel Adams?", "answer": "The Sierra Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a57d", "question": "Kodiak Island is the largest island in which US state?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ba", "question": "Which Seinfeld character takes his shirt off when he visits the toilet?", "answer": "George Costanza", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071dcf3745b36be73039de", "question": "What is the nationality of the first woman in space?", "answer": "Soviet/Russian", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5902a14acad1ec93f27df775", "question": "In a Cortado, what is the main purpose of the milk?", "answer": "To reduce the acidity of the coffee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b719", "question": "What carol contains the words \"Fa-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la\"", "answer": "Deck the Halls", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6ee", "question": "What does \"green lumber\" mean to carpenters?", "answer": "Lumber that is not yet dry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3701ff048f679a45ab12", "question": "Which Austrian psychiatrist penned \"The Interpretation of Dreams\" in 1900?", "answer": "Sigmund Freud", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca0e", "question": "Where in the body are the adenoids?", "answer": "Nasal cavity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a138", "question": "Who sang the theme song to the film \"The Breakfast Club\"?", "answer": "Simple Minds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff5129aff04d658268c92d1", "question": "What was the name of Woodrow Wilson's plan for peace after World War I?", "answer": "The Fourteen Points was a statement of principles for peace that was to be used for negotiations in order to end World War I.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8421ec223966ae8f87fc", "question": "Which actor played Keyser S\u00f6ze's lawyer and confidant, Kobayashi?", "answer": "Pete Postlethwaite", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6dd", "question": "What US city is serviced by the Hartsfield International Airport?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f16", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Robert Downey and Eddie Izzard?", "answer": "Charlie Chaplin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395aa", "question": "Who played Elliot Ness in the 1987 movie \"The Untouchables\"?", "answer": "Kevin Costner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a49220565ad31a57c7bf", "question": "Which President kept a 1,000+ lb. block of cheese in the White House?", "answer": "Andrew Jackson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b082", "question": "What famous woman became known as \"The Lady with the Lamp\" during the Crimean War?", "answer": "Florence Nightingale", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590722c63745b36be7303a02", "question": "What year did Mariah Carey release the song \"All I Want for Christmas Is You\"?", "answer": "1994", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071f333745b36be73039e9", "question": "What is Em Cypress' secret in the comic book series \"Revival\"?", "answer": "She is a reviver", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e75", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"A Patch of Blue\"?", "answer": "Elizabeth Hartman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ea", "question": "What term for an adult male gorilla comes from a distinctive patch of hair?", "answer": "Silverback", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf2", "question": "Who created the game Space Invaders?", "answer": "Tomohiro Nishikado", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef63fb6ce05a3942286e65", "question": "What singer gave up his seat on the plane that killed Buddy Holly?", "answer": "Waylon Jennings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be0d", "question": "What are the two fruit juices in a cosmopolitan?", "answer": "Cranberry and lime", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c31", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Carrie\" in 1973?", "answer": "Stephen King", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6bf", "question": "Which Amendment to the Constitution of the United States guarantees the right to a speedy trial?", "answer": "Sixth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339529", "question": "Who won an Academy Award for her role as Lisa Rowe in the 1999 movie \"Girl, Interrupted\"?", "answer": "Angelina Jolie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caa4", "question": "With what is sulfur and charcoal mixed to make gunpowder?", "answer": "Saltpeter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b137", "question": "In what year did the Soviet Union launch its first Sputnik satellite?", "answer": "1957", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f60301dd7bf43be5e82d", "question": "What annual event originated from the tradition of Candlemas?", "answer": "Groundhog Day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b35d", "question": "Who was the first American scientist to win a Nobel prize?", "answer": "Albert Michelson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab3f", "question": "Juba is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "South Sudan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339491", "question": "What highway were Mickey and Mallory travelling in the movie \"Natural Born Killers\"?", "answer": "Highway 666", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4cd", "question": "What seaport's name is Spanish for \"white house\"?", "answer": "Casablanca", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb0f", "question": "In what country is Guinness Stout brewed?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "general"}]